[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
all right everyone welcome to the stoa
still has a place for us to cohere
and dialogue about what matters most at
the knife's edge of this very moment
and i'm peter lindberg the steward of
the stoa
and today we are very very lucky because
we have my new friend
john thompson uh here today from
circling europe and i've been plugged
into the circling scene for a while now
friends with taylor joe here in toronto
friends with guy sangstock
um and i've been hearing so much about
this john thompson character
and then the whole circling europe crew
uh and how they have their own kind of
you know their own version of circling
that sounds very delicious
so i'm very um grateful that
john and i connected and that he's here
today at the stoa
so how today is going to work um we're
just going to record kind of the intro
portion of it then we'll probably stop i
think maybe at the 10-minute mark
and john is going to lead us through a
series of
exercises um i i guess he'll
he'll use this discernment if we're
going to go on breakout rooms or not um
yeah i think that's all i have to add so
that being said
i will take you in my friend
that was kind of like a violent pagan so
i i apologize if how that landed
slandered landed well thank you
thank you for inviting me and
it's really nice to be here i'm excited
to share this practice with you all
and i excited to come on the store
and connect this practice with
the high quality sense making that's
happening on this channel
to give you a bit of my background i've
i've been really passionate about
circling for the last 10 years and
me and my best friend once we learned
about it
we just practiced it and practiced it
together and after a few years we got
invited to lead somewhere and
there was something about the fact that
we had just been doing it non-stop for a
few years that really
touched people and we got invited to
lead it all over and we ended up
quitting our jobs that we had loads of
ambition in and
following this kind of movement to share
circling around the world
and after a few years of leading it this
thing happened where
we just we kind of had the group back
together again and we were
about to do the next thing and we we
just
looked at each other and like we just
couldn't
we couldn't do the thing that we were
meant to do and we're like what
like it doesn't feel right to speak so
we just
stayed quiet and the reason for that was
there was just this palpable
group presence and we were just like wow
we we need to listen to this we need to
just listen and go into the unknown from
here
and that was the birth of this thing
that we named surrendered leadership
which was a few years
we didn't come up with a name until a
few years later
and uh it's been a crazy beautiful ride
i see rob on here he stopped in in one
of our
workshops in new york about five or six
years ago i think when guy was there
with us
and we've we've kind of been deep in the
trenches of this
this practice which for me is very much
about getting into the territory
and that's what i'm excited to share
with you guys of like
hopefully there'll be some more some
sense making comes through all of this
but also we're really going to get into
the territory together
and hopefully get some kind of our aha
moments and experiences of so many of
the things that
this channel speaks about
and it was a couple of years ago with
with rebel wisdom coming out and
me hearing about sovereignty and all all
these things emergence collective
intelligence i was like
this is what we've been doing for seven
years wow there's other people out there
like
talking about this thing and they're
like yeah coherence this is this is
where it's at and
i was fortunate enough to do a
collective intelligence
um experiment with the rebel wisdom guys
last year and that was
super cool like bridging of these
different worlds
so that has me stoked to be here as well
to kind of because i think there's a lot
of
crossover between what we do and this
awesome sense making
so i was going to say something else
but i forgot think we'll just
dive in you you will need your
video on from now on because it's going
to be
experiential and practice based
yeah i remembered the thing that i was
gonna say
a final bit of kind of context around
this
we would so we were doing this practice
called surrendered leadership and what
we would find after a group
got quite into it was that we would
suddenly
witness this thing that was like
collective intelligence
and we had never we didn't really have a
reference point for collective
intelligence we hadn't read anything on
it
but we were just like ah like collective
intelligence
just seems to happen that was the
emerging property of
of surrendered leadership and since then
i've learned
a lot more about collective intelligence
and
but still that's that's the way i hold
it somehow through doing these kind of
presenting practices and like exploring
what's here and exploring what
connection is like
between us somehow when we do that and
we
surrender into the unknown often what
emerges out is some kind of
collective intelligence that we couldn't
have
we couldn't have pre-planned or we
couldn't have like had any idea of how
to
plan this beforehand
so with no further ado i'd like to
give you a first practice and i will put
you into breakout rooms for this
um peter i need
i don't